Shavelson, Clara Lemlich Miscellany 6131
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
Clara Lemlich Shavelson Miscellany
1909-1999
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
Shavelson, Clara Lemlich
6131
0.5 cubic feet
0.5 linear ft.
Papers.
5811472
General
Contact Information:
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives Martin P. Catherwood Library 227 Ives Hall Cornell University Ithaca, NY 14853 (607) 255-3183> kheel_center@cornell.edu http://www.ilr.cornell.edu/library/kheel-center
Compiled by:
Kheel Staff, July 11, 2011
EAD encoding:
Randall Miles, February 23, 2016
Conditions Governing Access
Access to the collections in the Kheel Center is restricted. Please contact a reference archivist for access to these materials.
Related Materials
Related Collections: 6131 AV: Clara Lemlich Shavelson Audio-Visual Materials 6131 P: Clara Lemlich Shavelson Photographs
5811472
- Correspondence, 1952-1982 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Clara Lemlich Shavelson: 50 years in Labor's Front Line, 1954 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  Scope and Contents
  By Paula Scheier, Jewish Life
- Vikhod v Bor'be (Box 1, Folder 3)
  Undated article in Russian
- Obituaries and memorial notices, 1982 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Articles about Clara Lemlich Shavelson, 1959-1999 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Handwritten notes, 1909-1951 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Morning Freiheit, 1959 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  November 22, 1959. In Yiddish.
- Morning Freiheit, 1959 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  November 29, 1959. In Yiddish and English.
- Morning Freiheit, 1982 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  September 17, 1982. Special New Year's Issue.
- Justice, 1959 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  November 15, 1959.
- Emma Lazarus Jewish Women's Clubs, 1970 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  August
- Remembering the Waistmakers General Strike, 1909, 1982 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  Clara Lemlich Shavelson, editor; Morris U. Schappes, author; Jewish Currents.
- Biography of Clara Lemlich Shavelson (Box 1, Folder 13)
  In Russian
- Travel log (Italy, Poland, USSR) (Box 1, Folder 14)
- "How Has Marriage Changed You?" (Box 1, Folder 15)
  Article in San Francisco newspaper